{
  "heading": "Select a topic",
  "topics": [
    {
      "heading": "INTRODUCTION AND BASICS",
      "questions": [
        {
            "questionNo": 1,
            "question": "What is the correct way to write a comment in Python?",
            "options": ["#Comment", "//Comment", "/*Comment*/", "< !--Comment-->"],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 2,
            "question": "What does input() function do?",
            "options": ["Prints output.", "Converts a value to an integer.", "Ends a program.", "Takes input."],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 3,
            "question": "What will be the output of the following code?<br>print(type(42))",
            "options": ["< class 'float' >", "< class 'int' >", "< class 'str' >", "< class 'bool' >"],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 4,
            "question": "What will be the output of the following code?<br>name = \"Aman\"<br>print(\"Hello, \" + name + \"!\")",
            "options": ["Hello, Aman!", "Hello name!", "Hello, Aman", "Syntax Error"],
            "answer": 0
        }
    ]   
    },
    {
      "heading": "ARITHMETIC OPERATORS",
      "questions": [
        {
            "questionNo": 5,
            "question": "What will be the output of the following code?<br>print(45%2)",
            "options": ["0", "1", "22", "22.5"],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 6,
            "question": "What will be the output of the following code?<br>print(10/2)",
            "options": ["0", "1", "5", "2"],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 7,
            "question": "What will be the output of the following code?<br>print(3**3)",
            "options": ["9", "6", "1", "27"],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 8,
            "question": "What is the datatype of the value returned by the input() function?",
            "options": ["str", "int", "float", "Depends on what the user has entered"],
            "answer": 0
        }
    ]
      
    },
    {
      "heading": "RELATIONAL OPERATORS AND CONDITIONAL PROGRAMMING",
      "questions": [
        {
            "questionNo": 9,
            "question": "What can be used to make decisions in programming?",
            "options": ["print()", "input()", "if statement", "None of the above"],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 10,
            "question": "Which operator is used to check if 2 values are not equal?",
            "options": ["==", "!=", "<", ">"],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 11,
            "question": "What does the == operator do in Python?",
            "options": [
                "Assigns a value to a variable",
                "Checks if two values are equal",
                "Checks if two values are not equal",
                "Compares if one value is greater than another"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        }
    ]
    
      
    },{
      "heading": "LOGICAL OPERATORS AND CONDITIONAL PROGRAMMING",
      "questions": [
        {
            "questionNo": 12,
            "question": "The and operator returns True if ______",
            "options": [
                "Any one condition is True",
                "All the conditions are True",
                "At least two conditions are True",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 13,
            "question": "What does the or operator do in Python?",
            "options": [
                "Returns True if both conditions are true",
                "Returns True if at least one condition is true",
                "Returns False if both conditions are false",
                "Both b and c"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 14,
            "question": "Which of the following statements is true about the not operator?",
            "options": [
                "It reverses the value of a relational operator.",
                "It checks if a condition is false.",
                "It combines two conditions where both must be true.",
                "It does nothing."
            ],
            "answer": 1
        }
    ]
    
      
    },
    {
      "heading": "STRINGS FORMATTING",
      "questions": [
        {
            "questionNo": 15,
            "question": "What will the following code print?<br>name=\"Neha\"<br>print(f\"Hello, {name}!\")",
            "options": [
                "Hello, Neha!",
                "Hello, {name}!",
                "Hello, name!",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 16,
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid string?",
            "options": [
                "\"Hello, World!\"",
                "'Hello, World!'",
                "\"\"\"Hello, World!\"\"\"",
                "Hello, World!"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 17,
            "question": "What will be the output of the following code?<br>sentence=â€™How are you?â€™<br>print(sentence[2:5])",
            "options": [
                "w ar",
                "ow are",
                "ow a",
                "w a"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 18,
            "question": "Which operator is used to concatenate strings in Python?",
            "options": [
                "*",
                "&",
                "|",
                "+"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        }
    ]
      
    },
    {
      "heading": "STRING METHODS",
      "questions": [
        {
          "questionNo": 19,
          "question": "Which method is used to convert a string to uppercase?",
          "options": [
              "s.upperCase()",
              "s.upper()",
              "s.to_upper()",
              "s.toUpper()"
          ],
          "answer": 1
      },
      {
          "questionNo": 20,
          "question": "Which method removes whitespace from the beginning and end of a string?",
          "options": [
              ".strip()",
              ".remove()",
              ".cut()",
              ".clear()"
          ],
          "answer": 0
      }
      ]
      
    },
     {
      "heading": "Project",
      "questions": [
        {
          "questionNo": 1,
          "question": "</ol> ðŸ‘‰ <a href='https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1JE-VFuLB4Js_RzlF2nlhEe9eTJr_oVnS?usp=sharing' target='_blank' class='button'>Let's Start</a> "
         
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
